Hey friends, the insurance policy of a private car, bike or
commercial vehicle is the
same, is there any difference in them?
Yes, there are a lot of differences in them, in terms of
pricing, terms and conditions
and coverage. Commercial vehicles are those
which we use
for commercial use and their
number plate is like Alto,
taxi, trucks, buses, pickup trucks etc.,
all these come under the commercial vehicle category.
So the topic about which
we will talk about add-on
is a very important add-on and its name is img23.
In today's video, we will learn what is img23 add-on,
why do
we need it in an insurance policy and after adding it,
how much percentage do we get
and what is the difference between zero depression and img23.
And at the end of the video, I will
also tell you how you can check in your policy whether
you have img23
add-on in it or not. Hello friends, my name is
Harvinder Singh and I welcome you to
DSC Solutions.  This channel
is trying to ensure that due to lack of any small or
big information, you do not suffer any financial loss related to
buying insurance or making any claim.
If you want to contribute in this, then
subscribe to the channel and do not
forget to share the information wherever necessary. Let's start the video, so
friends first of all let us know
what is img23. The full form of img23 is
Indian Motor Tariff 123 or MT. In the
list, it has number 23, hence it is
called mp33. Now why was it needed?
Because in the first
party i.e. comprehensive insurance
policy of commercial vehicles, there are some parts which are
not covered at all.
I will tell you the names of these parts, they are
length, tyre-tube, mudguard, bonnet, bumper, side
body and friends, if your policy is first
party and there is no 10 depression or img23 in your policy
and due to any claim, these
parts get damaged, then
you have not received even a claim of ₹1, hence I am  You should
take 2300 days in your policy.
Now if you take img23, then
how much percentage claim will you get?
I have just told you the list of these points, but
after taking img23, suppose a part gets
damaged from the first list, then first of all, the
depression is done from it, that is,
as old as your vehicle is, then according to the
decision of IRDA, after doing
depression, whatever amount
is left, the insurance company gives you 50% of that,
you have to pay that 50% from your pocket. For
example, let's understand that
suppose one part from this part list gets damaged, the
MRP of the part which gets replaced is ₹1000, first of all there will be
depression charge on it. For example, let's
assume depression at 15 percent. There is
fifteen percent of this much product, if we
add two thousand fifteen percent, then
eight and a half will be saved, half of eight and a half
means 425 will be given to you by the insurance company
and you will pay 425 rupees from your pocket.  If there
is 123 in the policy, then if
you are not 123 then you will have to pay the entire thousand
rupees from your pocket.
Now we know
what is the difference between Zero Depression and img23. See, there are two
reasons due to which it is different from
depression. First of all, it is much cheaper than
Zero Depression. If
you have to pay thousand rupees to add img23 in any commercial vehicle, then
if you want to get Zero Depend in the policy, then for that
you will have to pay 10 to 12 thousand rupees.
Yes friends, and the second
reason is that the
companies which introduce Jio, provide coverage for new vehicles only for the
first two-three years,
after that you do not get any kind of coverage,
whereas the period of the vehicle on the road can be
8, 10, 12 or even 15 years, so
what option do you have during that time?
It is IM 2023. Now we will know
how you can check in your policy whether there is
img23 coverage or not.
For this you  You have to go to the them section of your policy
as you can
see on the screen and here you will
see written in the them section Coverage
per Lamp Tyre-Tube Extra If you have
packed money against this then
your policy has img23 and if
you do not see anything like this written here
in the them section then your policy does
not have 2030 So friends,
I want to tell you one more important thing that whenever you
buy a commercial vehicle insurance policy,
you are definitely comparing your quotations to see
where
you are getting cheap insurance, so many times the insurance
consultant or agent, in order to give you cheap insurance,
remove img23 from it,
so you must check that img23 is
added, you should do whatever you can to
buy the policy only after doing the necessary research because it can cause a lot of
loss to you in the future, so
friends, I hope you have
understood the concept of img23 well and
you will be able to use all its features and benefits well,
similarly, see you
next week with important updated information,
next video  I'm here next Sunday until then take
care of yourself be happy think
thank you do that
[music]